ooh so a penalty each ends in a draw 22
the final score in Munich with the
deciding leg still to come in Madrid
what a cracking game that is going to be
next week uh thoughts anybody I just
thought it was an outstanding game if I
was being totally honest K I think T
wanted to see the tactics of Bayern I
think it was pretty much what he said I
think the Tactical change changing the
Wingers to other sides and going more
inside really helped injection of pace
but Real Madrid find a way to stay in
the game again for the first 20 minutes
it was out the game it was all Bayern
Munich but in the end they just managed
to do it and that man vishous J we've
talked about Bellum so many times we
talked about Rodrigo but venicius Jr
carries this team a long way what a
player he is Terry you said it Mah I
have to say you talk about toall at the
beginning Jimmy and and what he offered
tactically in the first half and in the
second half didn't work uh in the first
half because they just didn't punish
them uh by scoring they did punish them
after that and what they offered in the
second half you know we will we will
talk about it uh after as you said Real
Madrid finds a way to stay in games to
to to to be in a situation where they
were struggling at the beginning of the
game they go one n up two one down they
don't panic they don't panic they know
they would have an opportunity and they
had one and we'll talk about it Jimmy I
know you you're going to talk about the
the way Bayern defended at times um
yeah we'll do that later but when you
actually look at the stats here I mean
Bayern are on top in every metric except
the goals and we said that before the
game you know and and that's why we'll
all probably be saying before the next
game they're the favorites to get to the
finals veryone welcome back everybody
good to have you with us here in our
studio in London that's your thing isn't
it Michael come on in welcome into the
studio it's so good to have you still
with us Kate tierry Jamie and Micah um
Micah talked about the fact that you
were interested in seeing how Bayern
would approach the game what did you
make of how they did approach the game
and like Micah said that the Tactical um
the Tactical change by Thomas to I
thought it was brilliant the way they
they they wanted to have the Wingers
inside having s almost as a 10 position
on the left and on other side having
musala as a 10 position on the right
trying to attract them with the fullback
and go back straight inside uh they they
they they cut them at the beginning they
just didn't they just didn't they do
finish the position also of Miller same
position he took against laio in between
the left Center back and the left back
to make sure that they were not going to
come and have an impact on those on the
position of the two10 and then they
switch it in the in the second half
having think the Wingers areon wide Geto
playing as a 10 inside to make sure they
were going to isolate those guys but
this time in an inverted manner the
Lefty on the right the right player
white footed player sorry on the left
somebody just told me sorry that who was
showing whose notebook Micah you were
showing your notebook no because tiar G
some really good tactical an and his
position so I was just promp they saw it
on camera so they it was like Cru I tell
you it was an assist it was it was an
assist this show has come a long way
hasn't he Mikey Richard is telling t on
re about the tactics he reminded me
something I told
him he can't let you is that true true
or false it was nice nice I was just
saying it a really good point for mull I
just wanted to make sure you you
remember just putting Jimmy back to his
Lane good teammate my who's going to the
L I'm going to me Lane yeah Lane go back
to your lane the lane tomorrow I tell
you else need to go back to their Lane
oh Kim the defender
y for Bayern Munich the reason Bayern
Munich are in have beat Arsenal is
because Arsenal had a defender in the
face leg K who was not at the level and
he cost him he cost Arsenal in that face
leg him has costed Bayern Munich in this
first leg he really has because they've
been the dominant team they've been the
better team but they've Le been let down
by a Defender at the back and that's
what happened to Arsenal and Bayon
obviously capitalized on that but Real
Madrid looked like they will capitalize
on this from Bayern Munich penalty for
each side between Real Madrid and Bayern
Munich uh was it a fair result did you
think michah did it reflect the game uh
I thought Bayern were the better team in
terms of the metrics like Jamie said you
know passes possession all that sort of
thing but it doesn't matter matter why
you looking at me like that
Jamie your case no you said the no I was
just laughing that you it didn't sound
you saying the Met just it didn't sound
right no I don't know just I don't know
it was my word wasn't it I was just
saying that you were but I think the
overall game basically Bayern overall
were probably the better team but Real
Madrid the dug in and got the draw in
the end Jamie anything to add the metrix
no I I agree with I agree with M you
know the metrics the stats whatever you
want to call them they were in Bay's
favor oh my God what does it mean in
terms of going into the second leg
because obviously I think we already
generally thought when you're thinking
of the tie across the two legs you
thought of Real Madrid as the favorites
has anything changed no and I I think
that'll really hurt Bayern Munich
tonight psychologically because they
were the better team and they played
really well and they still didn't win at
home and there's this feeling I think
with Real Madrid whoever comes up with
against them because I've written them
off so often Champions League final
against Liverpool I couldn't see how
they'd beat Liverpool but they beat them
beating Manchester City in the in the uh
in the last round a couple of years ago
beating Manchester City and you think
you're scratching your head thinking
how's it happen but they've done it
again in terms of getting a result here
uh I Would S the second leg goals but I
think for Bay to play so well as well as
they did and still not win the game I
mean I don't know how sort of you know
psychologically they'll be able to
believe they can go to sort of the B
about and get through you agree with
that tiar yeah I mean I mean we go back
to the same thing I said it the other
day doesn't matter who run the most who
had the most chances who had the the the
most most possession with Madrid is
about taking your chances and yes again
we're going to talk it's pretty obvious
you don't take your chances you don't do
much with what you have when you're on
the ball and that's up to you mad will
you know we can take the life Li game
and you look at it and you're like how
how s didn't score three our open that
didn't score three in Madrid you take
the man city game you're like oh they
didn't touch the ball well they score
four goals though three there and one
and so again today two yes you can say
if there's a lot of if at the end of the
day when he comes to Madrid there's a
lot of if all the time I've been in that
situation you're like okay you you play
against a big team you have them you
don't you don't they execute stuff
that's what they do that's why you have
14 14 uh um offic Champions Leagues um
well over there in Munich p schichel and
g and balag watch this game live for us
at the stadium over there let's find out
their thoughts what did you think jent
well do you know it's amazing when you
watch a game on TV and then you watch it
live how different you see the game so
what I'm hearing here is the studio
actually thought B Munich played really
really well I don't think they did I
think they were very slow in the first
half they made some tactical changes yes
and it was a little bit better in the
second half but weren't really
threatening anything and we were sat
there talking about well they up against
Real Madrid they will hit them back and
and you know being two one up they they
should be a bit disappointed Defender
Kim on the first goal I don't know what
Kim's doing I don't know why he's giving
that penalty away they could have won
but they didn't play well do you think
they play well quite clearly there were
periods 20 minutes in the first half and
15 20 minutes in the second half that
they you were asking them you were
asking Bayan to actually speed things up
and they did and when they did they got
a result I find fascinating what
happened in the first 20 minutes in
which Real Madrid were like doesn't
matter we inferior we're considering
goals we'll have our moment goal and in
the second half exactly the same they go
21 down doesn't matter we'll have our
chances and then eventually they come so
that's the that's the head it's amazing
to watch Real Madrid play live in the
stadium there's no Panic at any time the
manager and shalot is just so calm all
the players they go one n two- n down
two1 down sorry and it's just calm
there's no Panic they just get along
with and you always sit there with a
sense of them striking back and of
course they did again again today and
the atmosphere oh just one word for it
I've been here a lot of times this is
the best I've ever been constant noisy
affecting the the the teams both teams
it was a greater spectacle one of the
big big and what's going to be next week
what a drama well Peter yes Peter would
you like some company tomorrow and we'll
see if the the West Farland Stadium can
match oh mun you know what are you
coming I'm coming yeah I'm telling you
what you're in for tomorrow okay go on
the yellow wall singing You Never Walk
Alone well how never seen anything me
and you join the dortman fans in the
yellow wall and sing You'll Never Walk
Alone no I'm never going to sing that
song