offer countless numbers of our alumni
and others around the world to enjoy the
facile manner in which they are able to
create meaningful connections that
result in lifelong relationships thank
you sir for staying on the mission of
making the world a more open place in
this time when elements of free
societies and cultures are making
concerted efforts to promote insularity
thank you also for collaborating with
your life partner and fellow alumna the
brilliant and talented dr. Priscilla
Chan a member of the great Harvard
College class of 2007 to create the Chan
Zuckerberg initiative and sign the
giving pledge that will provide
substantially all of your vast resources
two very important initiatives in the
fields of Technology Life Sciences and
education and as well as the promotion
of equality for the benefit of the
politically and economically
disenfranchised
and I would be remiss on this special
occasion if I did not say thank you for
using your t-shirt wardrobe to
demonstrate to the world that male
sartorial elegance doesn't always
present itself in a suit tie and
cufflinks most importantly thank you for
being with us today on our special day
ladies and gentlemen it is my high honor
to introduce dr. Mark Zuckerberg
I love this place thank you all for
coming out in the rain the pouring rain
we're going to make this worth it for
you president Faust Board of Overseers
faculty friends alumni proud parents
members of the ad board and graduates of
the greatest university in the world
I am honored to be here with you today
because let's face it you accomplished
something I never could if I get through
this speech today it'll be the first
time I actually finished something here
at Harvard class of 2017 congratulations
now I'm going to unlikely speaker today
not just because I dropped out but
because we're technically in the same
generation we walk this yard less than a
decade apart we studied the same ideas
and slept through the same act 10
lectures we may have taken different
roads to get here especially if you came
all the way from the quad but today I
want to share what I've learned about
our generation and the world we're all
building together but first these last
couple of days brought back a lot of
good memories how many of you remember
exactly where you were and what you were
doing when you got that email telling
you you got into Harvard
[Applause]
I was playing I was playing the video
games civilization and I ran downstairs
and got my dad and for some reason his
first reaction was to video me opening
the email that could have been a really
really sad video but I swear getting
into Harvard is the thing my parents are
most proud of me for my mom is nodding
you'll know what I'm talking about look
guys it's tough to beat this you'll see
when you get out there how many of you
remember your first lecture here at
Harvard mine was computer science 121
with the incredible Harry Lewis Harry I
[Applause]
was running late for class so I throw
out a t-shirt and I didn't realize until
afterwards I put it on inside out and
backwards my tag was sticking out the
front I couldn't figure out why no one
in class would talk to me except for
this one guy K X Gen he just went with
it we started doing our problem sets
together and now he runs a big part of
Facebook and that class of 2017 is why
you should be nice to people
[Laughter]
[Applause]
but my best memory from Harvard is
meeting Priscilla I had just launched
this prank website face mask and the ad
board wanted to see me everyone thought
I was going to get kicked out my parents
drove up here to help me pack my stuff
my friends threw me a going-away party
who does that
as luck would have it Priscilla was at
that party with her friends and we met
in line for the bathroom in the Fogo
bell tower and then what must be one of
the all-time most romantic lines I
turned her and said I'm getting kicked
out in three days so we need to go on to
date quickly actually any of you
graduating today can use that line I'm
getting kicked out today we need to go
on a date fast I didn't end up getting
kicked out I did that to myself
Priscilla and I started dating and you
know that movie made it seem like
Facemash was so important to starting
Facebook it wasn't but without say smash
I never would have met Priscilla and
Priscilla is the most important person
in my life
so you could still say it was the most
important thing I built in my time here
[Applause]
we have all started lifelong friendships
here and some of us even families that's
why I'm so grateful to this place
thanks Harvard today I want to talk
about purpose but I'm not here to give
you the standard commencement about
finding your purpose
we're Millennials we try to do that
instinctively instead I'm here to tell
you that finding your purpose isn't
enough the challenge for our generation
is to create a world where everyone has
a sense of purpose one of my favorite
stories is when JFK went to go visit the
NASA Space Center and he saw a janitor
holding a broom and he asked him what he
was doing and the janitor replied mr.
president I'm helping put a man on the
moon purpose is that feeling that you
are a part of something bigger than
yourself that you are needed and that
you have something better ahead to work
for purpose is what creates true
happiness and you are graduating at a
time when this is especially important
when our parents graduated that sense of
purpose reliably came from your job your
church your community but today
technology and automation are
eliminating many jobs membership in a
lot of communities has been declining
and a lot of people are feeling
disconnected and depressed and are
trying to fill a void in their lives as
I've traveled around I've sat with
children and juvenile detention and
opioid addicts who told me that maybe
their lives would have turned out
differently if they just had something
to do and after school program or
somewhere to go I've met factory workers
who know their old jobs aren't coming
back and we're just trying to find their
path ahead
for our society to keep moving forward
we have a generational challenge to not
only create new jobs but create a
renewed sense of purpose I remember that
night I launched Facebook from that
little dorm in Kirkland house I went to
Nokes with my friend kayaks and I
remember telling him clearly that I was
excited to help connect the Harvard
community but one day someone would
connect the whole world the thing is it
never even occurred to me that that
someone might be us we were just college
kids we didn't know anything about that
there are all these great big technology
companies with all these resources and I
just assumed one of them would do it but
this idea was so clear to us that all
people want to connect so we just kept
working on it day after day after day
and I know that a lot of you are going
to have your own stories just like this
a change in the world that seems so
clear that you are sure someone else is
going to do it but they're not you will
but it's not enough to have that purpose
yourself you also have to create a sense
of purpose for others and I found that
out the hard way you see my hope was
never to build a company I wanted to
have an impact and as all these people
started joining us I just assumed that
that's what they wanted to do too so I
never took the time to explain what it
was that I hoped we'd built a couple
years in some big companies wanted to
buy us I didn't want to sell I wanted to
see if we could connect more people and
we were building the first version of
newsfeed at the time and I thought if we
could just launch this it could change
how we all learn about the world nearly
everyone else wanted to sell without a
sense of higher purpose
this was their startup dream come true
and it tore our company apart after one
particularly tense argument one of my
closest advisors told me if I didn't
agree to sell the company right now
I would regret that decision for the
rest of my life relationships were so
afraid that within a year or so every
single person on our management team was
gone that was my hardest time meeting
Facebook I believed in what we were
doing but I felt alone and worse it was
my fault I wondered if I was just wrong
an impostor a 22 year old kid who had no
idea how things actually worked now
years later I understand it that is how
things work when there's no sense of
higher purpose so it's up to all of us
to create it so we can all keep moving
forward together and today I want to
talk about three ways that we can create
a world where everyone has a sense of
purpose by taking on big meaningful
projects together
by redefining equality so everyone has
the freedom to pursue their purpose and
by building community all across the
world so first let's take on big
meaningful projects our generation is
going to have to deal with tens of
millions of jobs replaced by automation
like self-driving cars and trucks but we
have the potential to do so much more
than that every generation has its
defining works more than three hundred
thousand people work to put that man on
the moon including that janitor millions
of volunteers immunize children around
the world against polio and millions of
more people built the Hoover Dam and
other great projects and now it's our
generations turn to do great things
now I know maybe you're thinking I don't
know how to build a dam I don't know how
to get a million people involved in
anything well let me tell you a secret
no one does when they begin ideas don't
come out fully formed they only become
clear as you work on them you just have
to get started if I had to know
everything about connecting people
before I got started I never would have
built Facebook movies and pop-culture
just get this all wrong
the idea of a single Eureka moment is a
dangerous lie it makes us feel
inadequate because we feel like we
haven't had ours yet and it prevents
people with seeds of good ideas from
ever getting started in the first place
oh and you know what else movies get
wrong about innovation no one writes
math formulas on glass okay all right
that's not a thing okay it's really good
to be idealistic but be prepared to be
misunderstood anyone working on a big
vision is going to get called crazy even
if you end up right anyone taking on a
complex problem is going to get blamed
for not fully understanding it even
though it's impossible to know
everything up front anyone taking
initiative will always get criticized
for moving too fast because there's
always someone who wants to slow you
down in our society we often don't take
on big things because we're so afraid of
making mistakes that we ignore all the
things wrong today if we do nothing the
reality is anything we do today is going
to have some issues in the future but
that can't stop us from getting started
so what are we waiting for
it is time for our generation defining
great works how about stopping climate
change before we destroy the planet and
getting millions of people involved
[Music]
manufacturing and installing solar
panels how about curing all diseases and
getting people involved by asking
volunteers to share their health data
track their health data and share their
genomes you know today our society
spends more than 50 times as much
treating people were sick as we invest
in finding cures so people get sick in
the first place
it makes no sense
we can fix this how about modernizing
democracy so everyone can vote online
and how about personalizing education so
everyone can learn these achievements
are all within our reach let's do them
all in a way that gives everyone in our
society a role let's do big things not
just to create progress but to create
purpose so taking on big meaningful
projects together is the first thing we
can do to create a world where everyone
has a sense of purpose
the second is redefining our idea of
equality so everyone has the freedom to
pursue their purpose now many of our
parents had stable jobs throughout their
careers but in order generation we're
all a little entrepreneurial whether
we're starting our own projects or
finding our role in another one and you
know that's great because our culture of
entrepreneurship is how we create so
much progress an entrepreneurial culture
thrives when it is easy to try lots of
new ideas Facebook wasn't the first
thing I built I also built chat systems
and games study tools and music players
and I'm not alone
JK Rowling got rejected 12 times before
she finally wrote and published Harry
Potter even Beyonce had to make hundreds
of songs to get Halo
the greatest successes come from having
the freedom to fail now today we have a
level of wealth inequality that hurts
everyone when you can't when you don't
have the freedom to take your idea and
turn it into a historic enterprise we
all lose and right now today our society
is way over indexed on rewarding people
when they're successful and we don't do
nearly enough to make sure that everyone
can take lots of different shots now
let's face it there is something wrong
with our system when I can leave here
and make billions of dollars in ten
years while millions of students can't
even afford to pay off their loans let
alone start a business look I know a lot
of entrepreneurs and I don't know a
single person who gave up on starting a
business because they were worried they
might not make enough money but I know
too many people who haven't had the
chance to pursue their dreams because
they didn't have a cushion to fall back
on if they failed we all know you don't
get successful just by having a good
idea or working hard you get successful
by being lucky - if I had to support my
family growing up instead of having the
time to learn how to code if I didn't
know that I was going to be fine
if Facebook didn't work out but I
wouldn't be standing up here today and
if we're honest we all know how much
luck we've had to get to this point in
our lives every generation expands its
definition of equality previous
generations fought for the vote and
civil rights they had the New Deal and
Great Society and now it's time for our
generation to define a new social
contract
we should have a society that measures
progress not just by economic metrics
like GDP but by how many of us have a
role we find meaningful we should
explore ideas like universal basic
income to make sure that everyone has a
cushion to try new ideas we're all going
to change jobs and roles many times so
we need affordable childcare to get to
work and healthcare that's not tied to
just one employer and we're all going to
make mistakes so we need a society
that's less focused on locking us up and
stigmatizing us when we do and as our
technology keeps on evolving we need a
society that is more focused on
providing continuous education through
our lives and yes giving everyone the
freedom to pursue purpose isn't going to
be free people like me should pay for it
and a lot of you are going to do really
well and you should too that is why
Priscilla and I started the Chan
Zuckerberg initiative and committed our
wealth to promoting equal opportunity
these are the values of our whole
generation it was never a question of if
we were going to do this the only
question was when Millennials are
already one of the most charitable
generations in history in just one year
more than three and four u.s.
Millennials donated to charity and more
than seven and ten raise money for
another one but it's not just about
giving money you can also give time and
I promise you if you just take an hour
to a week that's all it takes to give
someone a hand and help them reach their
potential now maybe you're thinking
that's a lot of time I'm not sure if I
have that much time I used to think that
you know when Priscilla graduated from
Harvard she became a teacher and before
she'd do education work with me she told
me that I needed to get my own
experience teaching a class at first I
complained you know I'm kind of busy
running this company but she insisted so
I taught an after-school program at the
local Boys and Girls Club on
entrepreneurship I taught those kids
lessons on product development and
marketing and they taught me what it was
like growing up feeling targeted for
your race and what it's like having a
family member in prison I shared stories
of my time in school and they shared
their hope that one day they would get
to go to college - for five years I've
had dinner with those students every
month one of them even through Priscilla
and me our first baby shower and next
year they're going to college every one
of them first-generation and their
families we can all make time to give
someone a hand let's give everyone the
freedom to pursue purpose not just
because it's the right thing to do but
because when more pee
can turn their dreams into something
great we are all better for it
purpose doesn't only come from work
the third way we can create a sense of
purpose for everyone is by building
community and in our generation when we
say purpose for everyone we mean
everyone in the world now quick show of
hands how many of you here are from
another country I now keep your hands up
how many of you are friends with one of
these folks now we're talking see we
have we have grown up connected in a
recent survey of Millennials around the
world asking what most defines our
identity the most popular answer wasn't
nationality ethnicity or religion
it was citizen of the world that's a big
deal every generation expands the circle
of people we consider one of us and in
our generation that now includes the
whole world we understand that the great
arc of human history bends towards
people coming together in ever greater
numbers from tribes to cities to nations
to achieve things that we could not on
our own we get that our greatest
opportunities are now global we can be
the generation that ends poverty that
ends disease and we get that our
greatest challenges need global
responses to no country can fight
climate change alone or prevent
pandemics progress now requires coming
together not just those cities or
Nations but also as a global community
but we live in an unstable time
there are people left behind by
globalization across the whole world and
it's tough to care about people in other
places well we don't first feel good
about our lives here at home there's
pressure to turn inwards this is the
struggle of our time the forces of
freedom openness and global community
against the forces of authoritarianism
isolationism and nationalism forces for
the flow of knowledge trade and
immigration against those who would slow
them down this is not a battle of
Nations is a battle of ideas there are
people in every country for more global
connection and there are good people
against it and this isn't going to be
decided at the UN either it's going to
happen at the local level when enough of
us feel a sense of purpose and stability
and our own lives that we can start to
open up and care about everyone else too
and the best way to do that is to start
building local communities right now
we all get a lot of meaning from our
communities who hears from Elliot house
how about Lowell I know you guys found
community because you literally live
right on top of each other and Mather
[Music]
I'll just leave that there whether our
communities are houses or sports teams
churches or acapella groups they give us
that sense that we were a part of
something bigger that we are not alone
they give us the strength to expand our
horizons and that's why it's so striking
that over the past few decades
membership in all kinds of communities
has declined by as much as one quarter
that's a lot of people who now need to
find a sense of purpose somewhere else
but I know that we can rebuild these
communities and start new ones because
many of you already are
I met Agnes ps-aguié who's graduating
today Agnes where are you Agnes spent
her childhood navigating conflict zones
with human trafficking in Uganda and now
she's trained thousands of law
enforcement officials to keep
communities safe
I met Kayla Oakley and Neha Jain
graduating today to stand up guys
Kayla Nia started a non-profit that
connects people suffering from chronic
illnesses with people in their
communities who are willing to help out
and I met David Rosner
who's graduating from the Kennedy School
today David stand up David is a former
city councilor who fought to make Mexico
City the first Latin American city to
pass marriage equality even before San
Francisco and this is my story - a
student in a dorm connecting one
community at a time and keeping at it
until one day we can connect the whole
world change starts local even global
change starts small with people like us
in our generation the struggle of
whether we connect more whether we
achieve our greatest opportunities comes
down to this your ability to build
communities and create a world where
every single person has a sense of
purpose
class of 2017 you are graduating into a
world that needs purpose and it's up to
you to create it now maybe you're asking
yourself can I really do this well
remember when I told you about that
class I taught at the Boys and Girls
Club one day after class I was talking
to my students about going to college
and one of my top students raised his
hand and said that he wasn't sure he
could go to college because he's
undocumented he wasn't sure if they'd
take him
last year I took him out to breakfast
for his birthday and I wanted to get him
a gift so I asked him what he wanted and
he just started talking about struggles
that he saw other students in this class
facing and finally said you know I'd
really just like a book on social
justice I was blown away here is a young
guy who has every reason to be cynical
he wasn't sure it's the country he calls
home the only one he's known was going
to deny him his dream of going to
college but he wasn't feeling sorry for
himself he wasn't even thinking of
himself he has a greater sense of
purpose and he is going to bring people
along with him it says something about
our situation today that I can't even
say his name because I don't want to put
him at risk
but if a high school senior who doesn't
know what the future holds for him can
do his part to move the world forward
then we owe it to the world to do our
part to
so before you walk out those gates one
last time
and as we sit here in front of Memorial
Church I'm reminded of a prayer
Misha Barak that I say whenever I face a
big challenge that I sing to my daughter
thinking of her future when I tuck her
in at night and it goes may the source
of strength whose blessed the ones
before us help us find the courage to
make our lives a blessing I hope you
find the courage to make your life a
blessing congratulations class of 2017
good luck out there
[Applause]
thank you so very much mark